<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-6812" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Creativity and Innovation District</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">My thoughts on the Creativity and Innovation District </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Outside of the CID (via housing.vt.edu)</title><image href="images/CIDoutside.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Outside of CID, a massive, looming stone brick and concrete building with many windows, especially on the bottom floor. A stone brick wall goes across the bottom of the image.</alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">History of the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">The Creativity and Innovation District (CID) is a very new building, opening in Fall 2021. It was constructed with modern features in mind, meant to best facilitate innovation and social interaction. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">What I Like About the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">CID is home. I have lived here for all my time at VT thus far, and am already lined up to live here for my final year as well. The rooms are a nice size, and the building has air conditioning which is great. Also the bathrooms are individual, which is great for me. </p><p class="- topic/p ">The Living-Learning Communities (LLCs) are the lifeblood of the building. Personally, I am a proud member of Studio 72, the community for arts and creativity. We have an amazing community lounge where we can go at any time to hang out with our fellow members, as well as lounges in the halls. Studio 72 also has a semesterly art showcase, held in the CID lobby. </p><p class="- topic/p ">CID itself also has events for all of its residents. My favorite is Monday Meals, where a bunch of CID residents go to Owens Hall to eat food together, alongside the faculty principal and his family. There is also Friday Friends, which can be pretty much anything, hosted by either the faculty principal or one of the three LLCs every Friday. One example of Friday Friends hosted by Studio 72 this semester was when we got the opportunity to learn about graffiti, and then spray paint a few walls designated for that purpose. It is fun to learn about new things, and Friday Friends is good for that. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">What I Dislike About the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">Recently, an issue has become more and more apparent that the building was not made with the most reliable materials. One of the elevators on my hall hasn't worked for most of the semester, and it isn't the first time I've seen an elevator malfunction in the building. One of the front doors has broken three separate times this semester as well. It just feels like the building is falling apart, but hopefully as things get fixed they are being made superior - but I don't know.</p><p class="- topic/p ">The only issue I have with the building conceptually would be that the student athletes live in CID. I know that sounds bad, but they do not participate in pretty much any of the building events, and I never interact with them in the halls or see other members of Studio 72 interact with them ever. It feels like this building was not designed for them, and that they should have a dorm more suited for their needs. There isn't a gym in CID, and you would think that would be useful for the student athletes to have. </p></section></body></topic>