<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-4560" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Shanks Hall</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">My thoughts on Shanks Hall</shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Outside of Shanks Hall (via vt.edu)</title><image href="images/shanksoutside.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Outside of Shanks Hall, a tall, blocky red brick building with many windows. Some greenery is present around the building.</alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">History of the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">Shanks Hall was first built in 1902, and named after David Carey Shanks Jr. It was originally a dorm building, before it was renovated in the 90s to become the home for the English and Communications departments. The most recent remodel was completed in 2001. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">What I Like About the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">Shanks is home for both of my majors (Creative Writing and Professional &amp; Technical Writing), so I have most of my classes here nowadays. Having a lot of classes in one building tends to get one somewhat attached to it - as long as the building isn't terrible. There is also a free book exchange shelf on the third floor, so that's cool. I haven't found anything I want there yet, but I need to check more often. </p><p class="- topic/p ">The classrooms are nice. They have decent technology, and most importantly they are perfectly air-conditioned. Some of the classrooms have a bunch of computers available for anyone who doesn't have one strong enough for some projects. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">What I Dislike About the Building</title><p class="- topic/p ">The crooked stairs - although extremely funny - are also vaguely annoying. It is also simply a mind-boggling design choice in general. The hilarity of it is always great to tell people who have never set foot in Shanks, though, so it really isn't all bad. </p><p class="- topic/p ">I  know that this is a really small personal thing, but I wish the English part wasn't three stories up. I never have classes anywhere but the third floor, and it would be so convenient to have them on the ground floor instead. This also exacerbates my complaints about the funny stairs.</p></section></body></topic>